开萝尔:"等一下,我听不到你说什么."
Carol: Wait, I can't hear you.
电视:"好了,保罗.我明白那些纳粹的事情,但是为什么你们这些人要穿着红色格子短裙呢?这不是短裙,这是连帽衫."
TV: Ok Paul.I understand about the Nazi thing, but why are you guys wearing red platted skirts?It's not a skirt, it's a jumper.
开萝尔:"本,珊迪说的话我一句都听不清了."
Carol: Ben, I can't hear a word Sandy's saying.
本:"嘘."
Ben: Shhh.
茱丽:"孩子们,我刚要哄克瑞西睡午觉,你们能不能安静一点?"
Julie: You guys.I just put Chrissy down for a nap.Can you please be quiet?
(宝宝在哭.)
(Baby crying)
杰森:"嘿,孩子们,让我休息一下吧,我还有工作要做呢."
Jason: Hey guys.Give me a break.Come on.I've got to do some work.
开萝尔:"我只是想在这里打一个电话而已."
Carol: I'm just trying to carry on a simple conversation here.
电视:"你们为什么要剃头?我没有剃头,克鲁斯蒂剃了."
TV: Why do you shave your head?I don't.Crusty does.
杰森:"好了,第一,这里太吵了;第二,到时候该……"
Jason: Come on.First of all it's too loud.Secondly it's time to...
麦克:"嘿,爸爸,你能帮我检查一下我的家庭作业吗?我刚才说什么了?"
Mike: Hey dad.Would you please check out my homework assignment?What did I say?
杰森:"你刚才说什么了?麦克,12年来,你从来没有一次要我帮你检查家庭作业,我不知道要说什么了."
Jason: What did you say?Mike in twelve years you've never asked me to check out your homework.I don't know what to say.
麦克:"恩,我只是想让你看一下我在心理学作业上的分数."
Mike: Well I just want you to check out the grade I got on this psychology assignment.
杰森:"当然可以了,哦,太好了.嘿,这对我来说意义太重大了,你不知道,你拿了个……C减."
Jason: Sure.Yeah great.Hey this means a lot to me.You have no idea.For you to come to...a C minus!
麦克:"对了,这就是我想要说的."
Mike: Yeah.That's what I want to talk about.
杰森:"我等了12年,就等到个C减."
Jason: I wait twelve years.I get a C minus.
麦克:"爸爸,你瞧,我拼了全力得了这个分数,你知道吗,我的意思是我本应该得个B.我想这门课的老师讨厌我,你是精神病医师,你能给我看看我的答案吗?"
Mike: Dad, look.I worked my butt off for that grade, you know.I mean I should have deserved a B.I think the teacher just hates me.You're a psychiatrist.Would you just check my answers?
杰森:"喔,你甚至还没有忘记我是靠什么谋生的,我先坐下."
Jason: Wo.You even remember what I do for a living.I better sit down.
麦克:"你是知道的,塞欧遇到麻烦的时候,比尔科斯比从来都不笑话他的."
Mike: You know when Theo has a problem, Bill Cosby never jokes.
杰森:"好的,现在我来看看,让我看看.普通心理学情结的定义.这是你的第一个问题.是恋母情结而不是可食用情结."
Jason: Ok, now look.Let's see.Common definitions of common psychological complexes.There's your first problem.It's an oedipo complex Mike, not an edible complex.
麦克:"这是心理学课,不是拼写课.我是说重点是我写出了正确的答案,就是一个人想要约会他的妈妈."
Mike: This is a psych class, not a spelling class.I mean the point is I put down the right answers.It's when a guy wants to date his mum.
本:"那么你可真幸运,我们把约会他们妈妈的人叫作多纳休."
Ben: Then you're in luck.It's guys who date their mums, we call the Donahue.
麦克:"当我想要点芥末的时候总是找不到."
Mike: There's never any mustard around when you are in the mood for something oedipo.
茱丽:"麦克,晚饭在烤炉里,所以不要弄得哪都是."
Julie: Mike, dinners in the oven, so don't fill up on all of that.
麦克:"你看,我只是要找点东西吃,行不行啊?"
Mike: Look.I'm just trying to get something to eat.Would that be ok with you?
茱丽:"不要跟我一般见识."
Julie: Well excuse the holy heck out of me.
麦克:"嘿,你是在说我,嘿,你瞧,茱丽,别这样,我不是要跟你对着干,只是,我不知道这些日子以来,你有一天是完全地……"
Mike: Hey.You cursed at me.Hey look Julie, come on.I didn't mean to snap at you.It's just that, I don't know, ever had one of those days when you just feel completely...
茱丽:"我一直都是这样."
Julie: All the time.
茱丽:"然后我想到你,就觉得好一点."
Julie: and then I just think about you, and I feel better.
麦克:"是真的吗?"
Mike: Really?
茱丽:"是真的."
Julie: Really.
麦克:"啊,嘿,怎么样呢?我觉得好多了,我喜欢这样的感觉."
Mike: Ahh.Hey, how about that.I feel better.I'd love to feel great.
茱丽:"麦克,你爸爸在起居室呢,你不想让他看到我们的吧."
Julie: Mike.Your dad's in the living room.You don't want him to find out about us.
麦克:"对,对,对.但是今晚我们还是要在你家一起学习呢,对吧?"
Mike: Right, right, right.But we're still going to study together tonight at your place, right?
茱丽:"说定了."
Julie: You bet.
麦克:"好的."
Mike: Right.
茱丽:"关键是学习."
Julie: The key word is study.
麦克:"对我来说,关键是我们在一起.当然,另一个关键是你家.实际上有两个关键之处:你和你家,但是,恩……"
Mike: The key word for me was together.Of course, the other key word was your place.Actually that is two key words; your and place, but uh...
茱丽:"那7点见了."
Julie: I'll see you at seven.
麦克:"好."
Mike: Ok.
茱丽:"这次记得要把书带来."
Julie: And this time, bring your books.
杰森:"嘿,麦克,你瞧,我知道你很沮丧,而且……"
Jason: Hey Mike, look I know you are upset and...
麦克:"什么?哦,哦,对啊,爸爸你也知道我确实很沮丧,你知道吗,这个C减让我好怀念以前我不好好学习,最后得到个烂成绩的那些日子."
Mike: About what?Oh, oh, right.You better believe I'm upset dad.You know this C minus really makes me miss the days when I never studied and got crummy grades.
杰森:"是啊,那些日子确实不错."
Jason: Yeah.That was some great times.
麦克:"你知道吗,那时候我还为C减花过大把的钱呢,有好几次."
Mike: You know back then, I would have paid big bucks for a C minus.A couple of times I did.
杰森:"你说什么?"
Jason: Pardon me.
麦克:"随便说说,没什么的,爸爸"
Mike: Just an expression dad.
杰森:"嘿,麦克,我现在很高兴看到你为好成绩而努力.我是说,基于你以前的学习成绩来说,这个分数实数不易了,我的意思是我在夸奖你."
Jason: Hey Mike, I'm just pleased that you are now trying for good grades.I mean that alone is quite an accomplishment for somebody with your pitiful academic record.I mean that as a compliment.
麦克:"嘿,爸爸,罗森费尔德教授是个十足的笨蛋."
Mike: Hey dad, Professor Rosenfeld is a complete bozo.
杰森:"等一下,或许他对你们严格是有原因的,到了大学,竞争更激烈了,你需要更加认真.对于你来说,以前糊里糊涂无所谓,但是现在是肯定不行的了."
Jason: Wait a minute.Maybe he's being tough ion you for a reason.In college, the competition is tougher.You have to be more precise.Say what you mean.That unclarity which was ok before is now, clearly it's unclear.
麦克:"你刚才说的话我听不明白."
Mike: I have no idea what you just said.
杰森:"那么我就说得再清楚一些."
Jason: Well let me be more precise.
麦克:"嘿,没那个必要了,因为我以后不会再上他的课了."
Mike: Hey, it doesn't matter because I am dropping that class tomorrow.
杰森:"你以后不上心理学课了?那是我最爱的一门课."
Jason: You are going to drop Psychology?My first love.
麦克:"我整个学期都非常用功,真的,但是还是不能让这个老师觉得满意.我是说,他要我把所有补好的作业明天交给他,这样能把C减改成C."
Mike: I have been working hard all semester.Really working, but I just can't seem to please this guy.I mean he says I have to hand in all this make-up work tomorrow, just to bring my C minus up to a C.
杰森:"是啊,我在大学的时候也有一个像罗森费尔德这样的老师,对细节非常严苛,他的名字是汉库克博士,我现在一点都不想告诉你我们过去是怎么称呼他的.好多年后我才知道他只是在帮我达到最好的程度.我想你最终也会意识到的……千万别放弃这门课程."
Jason: Yeah, well I had a teacher like Rosenfold in college too.A real stickler for detail.His name was Doctor Hancock.I didn't even want to tell you what we used to call him.It took me years to figure out that he was just trying to get the best out of me.I think you'll realize that too.Just don't give up the class.
麦克:"恩,如果你认为……"
Mike: Well if you think that...
杰森:"嘿,在你以后的人生中,你会遇到很多跟你过不去的人,让你接受不共正的待遇.我是说现在是老师,以后还会是同事,然后会是老板,最终会是你的妻子."
Jason: Hey for the rest of your life you're going to find people who are tough on you when you don't really deserve it.I mean first of all it's a teacher, then it's going to be a co working, then a boss and finally a wife.
麦琪:"关妻子什么事?"
Maggie: What about a wife?
杰森:"我只是在告诉麦克,没有妻子,生活就不可能继续."
Jason: I was just telling Mike that without a wife, life would be impossible.
麦琪:"那么谢谢你了,宝贝."
Maggie: Well thank you honey.
杰森 :"不客气,亲爱的."
Jason: You're welcome my darling.
麦克:"哦,这回我可知道了."
Mike: Boy, and the wonder where I get it.
麦琪:"哦,杰森,你看过了麦克的家庭作业,打分真的很不公平吗?"
Maggie: Ok Jason, you looked at Mike's homework.Was it graded unfairly?
杰森:"麦克的答案不准确.我告诉他在大学里,尤其是心理学,要求的是他过去所没有达到的精确度.是的,他需要具备清晰的表达能力,不夸张的说,以前可以接受的程度已经完全不行了."
Jason: Mike's answers are imprecise.I told him that in college, especially psychology, it requires a certain clarity that he's not used to.Yes he needs to have an ability to communicate clearly, without the hyperbole, which while acceptable before is now clearly unclear.
麦琪:"我不知道你刚才说的是什么."
Maggie: I have no idea what you just said.
杰森:"比如说在幼儿园里,还记得麦克以前抱怨说克林太太让他用最硬的黏土,然后我去那里看了看,我告诉他说'麦克,你的黏土跟其他小朋友们的一样软.'现在,我又做了同样的事情."
Jason: It's like in kindergarten.Remember how mike used to complain that Mrs.Kling made him work with the hardest clay.Then I went down there and I pointed out "Mike, your little piles just as soft as the other kids".I've done it again.
麦琪:"你说什么?"
Maggie: Pardon me.
杰森:"恩,我只是告诉他在他的一生中,会遇到给他不公正待遇的人,先是老师,然后是老板,同事,最后是妻子,终其一生,生活是艰辛的!你得在那里."
Jason: Well I just told him that all through his life he's going to run into people that make it tough for him over ways he's doesn't even deserve.First of all it's going to be a teacher, then a boss, then a coworker, finally it's a wife-fool ourselves, life's tough!You had to be there.
麦琪:"没错,我是."
Maggie: I was.
杰森:"我告诉他汉库克博士的事情,还记得吗?记得当时我有多恨他,然后变得尊敬他,对,敬畏他."
Jason: I told him about Dr Hancock.Remember?Remember how I hated that guy, then I grew to respect him, yea revere him.
麦琪:"敬畏他!杰森你至今还在恨他.你在同学会时甚至不愿跟他握手.哈哈,你还叫他那个让人讨厌的外号."
Maggie: Revere him!Jason you still hate him and you wouldn't even shake his hand at the reunion.And ha ha ha you called him that awful nickname.
杰森:"麦琪,我已经是个父亲了.不要让实际所发生的事情把这一切搞砸."
Jason: Maggie, I was parenting.Don't muddy things up with the way they really happened.
麦琪:"哦,杰森,你还没有真正回答我的问题呢,他是要放弃那门课,还是别的怎么样?"
Maggie: Oh Jason, you still haven't really answered my question.Is he going to drop the class, or what?
杰森:"嘿,现在他在他的房间里,补作业呢,他已经上了很有价值的一课."
Jason: Hey, right now he's up in his apartment, he doing his make up assignment and he's leaned a valuable lesson.
麦琪:"你确定吗?"
Maggie: You're sure about that?
杰森:"亲爱的,我做事,你放心.
Jason: Honey, when the old communicator steps in, you can put that in the bank.
(走进麦克的房间)麦克,是我,我给你拿来些点心,麦克?麦克,你在吗?嘿."
(Goes to Mike's room) Mike, it's only me.Brought a little snack to study with.Mike?Mike, you in there?Hey.
麦克:"嘿,爸爸."
Mike: Hey dad.
杰森:"你应该在你房间里补你的心理学作业啊."
Jason: You're supposed to be studying for your psychology make up assignment.
麦克:"啊,是的,是的,我写完了.啊,就在那里呢,等我一会."
Mike: Ah, yeah, yeah.I did it.Yeah it's right here dad.Just give me a minute.
杰森:"算了,别装了,我知道你出去玩了."
Jason: Come on, Cut the drama.I know you've been out goofing around.
麦克:"我没有去玩,我是跟茱……犹太人一起学习呢."
Mike: I have not been goofing around.I was studying with Juuuuuuwish people.
杰森:"你说什么?"
Jason: What?
麦克:"是啊,还有一些基督教徒,恩,一些无神论者和穆斯林教徒,嘿,教育是不分宗教派别的."
Mike: Yeah.And some Christians and uh, some atheists and Muslims.Hey, education has no religion.
杰森:"显然,我的话对你一点作用也没有,麦克."
Jason: Obviously my little talk with you meant nothing Mike.
麦克:"啊,啊,想起来了,我知道了我把作业忘在她……何比家了."
Mike: Ah ha.Here it is.I knew I didn't leave it at herrrrrrbies.
杰森:"何比是谁?"
Jason: Who's Herbie?
麦克:"啊,他是,啊.他是跟我一起学习的犹太人,你在听吗?"
Mike: Ah, he's ah, he's that Jewish guy that I was studying with.Weren't you listening?
杰森:"让我想想."
Jason: Let me see that.
杰森:"你真的补完你的作业了?"
Jason: You actually finished your makeup assignment.
麦克:"是."
Mike: Yeah.
杰森:"想吃饼干吗?"
Jason: Want a cookie?
麦克:"不了,谢谢.我恩,刚才吃了好多东西在,恩,我还是去洗澡,这样安全一点."
Mike: No thanks.I, urm, had a big meal over at, urm, it would be safer if I went to the bathroom.
杰森:"我的工夫还是没有白费,这孩子毕竟还是听进去我说的话了.这个对,对,错,错错.麦克,过来,你交作业以前需要再好好检查一遍."
Jason: So I'm not crazy.I'm getting to that boy after all.That's good, good, bad bad bad.Mike come on.You've got to double check your answers here before you turn them in.
麦克:"嘿,那又能怎么样呢?罗森费尔德不会对我满意的."
Mike: Hey what's the point?Rosenfelds got it in for me.
杰森:"他不是对你不满意,麦克,他是对不认真的作业不满意.还记得幼儿园的黏土吗?"
Jason: He doesn't have it in for you Mike.He's got it in for sloppy work.Remember that clay in kindergarten?
麦克:"嘿,我还是会说克林太太总是塞给我硬硬的黏土."
Mike: Hey I still say Miss Kling stuck me with stiff clay.
杰森:"我怎么才能让你明白呢?好吧,让他看看准确的答案能得到怎样的成绩,试试吧."
Jason: How am I going to get you to understand?Well, let's show him what kind of grade precise answers get.Hu.Try that.
杰森:"嘿,本,怎么了?"
Jason: Hey Ben.What's up?
本:"帮我看看我的数学作业吧."
Ben: Well I need some help with my math homework.
杰森:"好的,等一下,哦,我得先跟麦克谈谈,你再等一会."
Jason: Sure.Just a second.Oh but I got to talk to Mike first.Just stand by.
本:"只要有东西吃就行."
Ben: As long as I can eat.
杰森:"哦,你补的心理学作业怎么样了?"
Jason: So, how did you do in that psychology makeup assignment?
麦琪:"不太好,我今天没去上课,本,你怎么了?"
Maggie: Not well, I cut class today.How you doing Ben?
本:"在等爸爸."
Ben: Standing by.
杰森:"我还以为你是麦克呢."
Jason: I thought you were Mike.
麦琪:"恩,也差不多了,在红绿灯的时候他就在我后面,怎么了?嗨,麦克."
Maggie: Well, you were pretty close.He was behind me at the stop light.Why what's going on?Hi Mike.
杰森:"哦,你补的心理学作业怎么样了?"
Jason: So how did that darn psychology make up go?
麦克:"气死我了,他给了我个D."
Mike: I ate it.He gave me a D.
杰森:"啊,哈哈,你认为他为什么会给你一个这么好的D……呢?"
Jason: Ah ha ha.And why do you suppose he gave you such a goo...a D!
麦克:"嘿,我知道,我本应该至少得B的."
Mike: Yeah I know.I should have deserved at least a B.
杰森:"不要说B了,你本应该的得A的."
Jason: Well never mind a B, you should have gotten an A.
麦琪:"哦,杰森,不要太过分了."
Maggie: Oh Jason, let's not get carried away here.
杰森:"不,我告诉你,所有这些答案都是正确的."
Jason: No, I tell you.All of these answers are correct.
麦克:"你肯定吗?"
Mike: You bet they are.
杰森:"我知道的,我写的."
Jason: I know they are.I wrote them.
麦克和麦琪:"你说什么?"
Mike and Maggie: What?
杰森:"不是麦克西佛尔得了D,而是杰森西佛尔博士."
Jason: Mike Seaver didn't get a D here.Doctor Jason Seaver did.
本:"啊,爸爸,恕我冒犯,不过我想我还是自己做作业吧."
Ben: Ah dad.No offence, but I think I'll figure my homework out by myself.
麦琪:"你做了麦克的心理学作业,然后得了个D?"
Maggie: You wrote Mike's Psychology answers and got a D?
杰森:"恩……"
Jason: Well...
麦克:"你自己都不明白这些问题,你还收别人的钱?"
Mike: You don't know this stuff and you are charging people?
杰森:"这些答案都是正确的啊,我也不明白."
Jason: All of these answers are correct.I don't understand it.
麦克:"那么我知道了,因为上面是我的名字,所以正确的答案也会给判成错的."
Mike: Well I do.If my name is on that paper, right answers are marked wrong.
麦琪:"麦克,别这样,又成了黏土那事了."
Maggie: Mike, you are getting carried away here.This is the clay thing all over again.
麦克:"嘿,你瞧,妈妈,你可以教训我,但是这个你要怎么说明呢?爸爸,今天以前我还不能确定是否要放弃这门课程,不过我真得好好谢谢你."
Mike: Hey look mum.You can argue with me, but you can't argue with this.Dad, I wasn't sure about dropping this course until today, but I can't thank you enough.
杰森:"这本来应该凑效的啊,麦琪,这是一个很棒的点子."
Jason: This should have worked Maggie.It was a great idea.
麦琪:"你要收病人们多少钱?"
Maggie: How much do you charge your patients?
杰森:"啊哈."
Jason: Ah ha.
麦琪:"杰森,现在是凌晨两点,你在干什么?"
Maggie: Jason, it's two o'clock in the morning.What are you doing?
杰森:"麦琪,我刚刚把麦克作业里的每一个问题都看过了,每一个答案都是百分百绝对正确的."
Jason: Maggie, I just looked up every single one of the questions on Mike's assignment and every one of my answers is absolutely one hundred percent correct.
麦琪:"那就是说麦克说的没错,是他的教授的不公正了."
Maggie: So that means that Mike is right about this professor being unfair.
杰森:"恩,可能是,或者还有什么别的原因,比如可能是助教给作业打的分数,我也做过助教,我也批改过学生的作业,那时侯我都不知道我在做什么."
Jason: Well he could be.Or it could be something else, like maybe a teacher's assistant graded this paper.Well I was a TA, I graded undergraduate papers, and I didn't know what I was doing.
麦琪:"你肯定不知道,杰森,我要去学校,找那个蠢材教授理论."
Maggie: You sure didn't.Jason, I want to go down and give this bozo professor a piece of my mind.
杰森:"麦琪,冷静,那是大学,如果妈妈去学校找教授理论的话,那么麦克会怎么想?"
Jason: Maggie, come on.This is college.How is Mike going to feel if his mummy goes down to talk to the professor?
麦琪:"他一定觉得很尴尬."
Maggie: He'd be embarrassed.
杰森:"是的,别这样,因为我对黏土那件事的处理,他现在还不能释怀.跟老师谈话是绝对错误的."
Jason: Embarrassed!Come on, he's still bitter about the scene I made over the clay.Talking to the teacher would be absolutely the wrong thing to do.
杰森:"打扰一下,嗨,我是杰森西佛尔,我想跟你谈谈有关我儿子的事情."
Jason: Excuse me.Hi I'm Jason Seaver.I would like to talk to you about my son.
看门人:好的.
Janitor: Ok.
杰森:"作为同行,我想至少要让他感受到我们这个领域的奇幻与奥妙之处是非常重要的."
Jason: Speaking colleague to colleague, I think it's important for him to be exposed at least to the excitement and the wonder of our field.
看门人:"一点不错."
Janitor: I couldn't agree more.
杰森:"恩,我担心他没有公正地看待过这门课程就要放弃."
Jason: Well I'm just afraid that he's going to drop out without giving it a fair shot.
看门人:"啊,那真是可惜,但是作为同行,如果你儿子不想成为一个看门人,为什么还要阻拦他呢?"
Janitor: Ah, well that would be a shame.But colleague to colleague, if your kid don't want to be a janitor why push him.
杰森:"看门人."
Jason: A janitor.
看门人:"你好,博士."
Janitor: Yo doctor.
杰森:"你是罗森费尔德博士?"
Jason: You are Dr Rosenfeld?
罗森费尔德:"是的."
Rosenfeld: Yes.
杰森:"我恩,我是杰森西佛尔,麦克西佛尔的爸爸."
Jason: I'm uh, I'm Jason Seaver.I'm Michael Seaver's dad.
罗森费尔德:"麦克西佛尔,麦克西佛尔."
Rosenfeld: Mike Seaver.Mike Seaver.
杰森:"是的,他上您的心理学课,卷发,很有趣的孩子."
Jason: Yes.He's in your intro to psych class.Curly hair, funny kid.
罗森费尔德:"有300个学生上我的课,其中至少有100个都是卷发,而且他们都认为自己很有趣."
Rosenfeld: Well I've got three hundred students in that lecture class.At least a hundred of them have curly hair.All of them think they are very funny.
杰森:"我了解,我来是想或许我们可以说明一下他补交作业中的一些问题."
Jason: I bet.Well I just came here to maybe clear up a little misunderstanding over his make up assignment.
罗森费尔德:"等一下,如果有什么不寻常的事情的话,我都会做记录的."
Rosenfeld: Excuse me, but I always like to make a note when something bizarre happens.
杰森:"不寻常?"
Jason: Bizarre.
罗森费尔德:"荒谬的,滑稽的,奇怪的."
Rosenfeld: Preposterous, ludicrous, queer.
杰森:"是,我知道那是什么意思,是的."
Jason: Yes, I know what it means.Yes.
罗森费尔德:"在我担任大学教授的这些年来,我从来没有跟学生家长谈过话."
Rosenfeld: In all my years as a college professor, I've never had a parent teacher conference.
杰森:"哦,别把我当成学生家长就行了."
Jason: Oh well don't think of me as a parent.
罗森费尔德:"哦,那么你不是家长吗?"
Rosenfeld: Oh, so you're not a parent?
杰森:"不,不,是的,我是家长,但是如果可以的话,我想跟您进行一场同事间的谈话."
Jason: No, no, yes I am a parent.But I would like to talk to you, if I may, colleague to colleague.
罗森费尔德:"同事?"
Rosenfeld: Colleague!
杰森:"同辈,同行,从事同样工作的."
Jason: Equal, comrade, peer.
罗森费尔德:"合伙人,同门,伙伴,我还能继续下去."
Rosenfeld: Associate, co-agiter, messmate.I could go on.
杰森:"真希望能编成本书,我是精神病医师."
Jason: I wish I had a little book to write in.I am a psychiatrist.
罗森费尔德:"哦,你怎么不早点说呢?请坐,请坐,这太好了,你是从事教育心理学的吗?"
Rosenfeld: Oh, well why didn't you say so?Please sit down sir.Sit down, that's wonderful.Are you an educational psych?
杰森:"不是,我开私人诊所."
Jason: No, private practice.
罗森费尔德:"哦,那很不错,我自己也差点跟你一样."
Rosenfeld: Oh, that's great.I almost went that route myself.
杰森:"恩,弄来张皮沙发放在这里,你在那里就行了."
Jason: Well, just invest in a leather couch here and you are half way there.
罗森费尔德:"吸烟吗?"
Rosenfeld: Pipe?
杰森:"不,我不吸烟,谢谢."
Jason: No, I don't smoke.Thank you.
罗森费尔德:"我也不吸,那么西佛尔博士,您有何贵干呢?"
Rosenfeld: Neither do I.So, doctor Seaver, what's on your mind?
杰森:"恩,是为了我儿子补交的心理学作业而来.似乎是您,或者更像是您的助教错判了."
Jason: Well, it's this darn makeup assignment in psych.It seems that you, more likely one of your teacher's assistance, may have misgraded it.
罗森费尔德:"错判?"
Rosenfeld: Misgraded?
杰森:"是啊,您看这儿,这个."
Jason: Yeah, like right there.This one.
罗森费尔德:"我没有助教,也从没错判过作业.如果旁边有红色的标记,那么肯定是错了."
Rosenfeld: I don't use TA's and I don't misgrade papers.If there's a crimson check mark next to it, it's wrong.
杰森:"错了?不相信我?这道题没有错,我仔细检查过了."
Jason: Wrong, no believe me.This one's not wrong.I checked this one carefully.
罗森费尔德:"我也仔细检查过了."
Rosenfeld: So did I.
杰森:"那好吧,我指给你看.比如说:A)佛洛伊德分析,B)Youngian分析,C)Transactional分析,D)A和B没有C,E)A和C没有B,F)B和C没有A,G)以上所有.很明显E是正确答案,可是你却判错了."
Jason: Ok, well let me show you here.For example; A) Freudian analysis B)Youngian analysis C)Transactional analysis D) A and B but not C E) A and C but not B F) B and C but not A G) All of the above.E is clearly the right answer, and yet it's marked wrong.
罗森费尔德:"不是错,是不准确."
Rosenfeld: It's not as much wrong as it is imprecise.
杰森:"不准确?"
Jason: Imprecise?
罗森费尔德:"模棱两可,意义不明."
Rosenfeld: Ambiguous, unclear.
杰森:"没错,我知道这是什么意思,是的,怎么就不准确了呢?"
Jason: Yes, I know what it means.Yes, how is that imprecise?
罗森费尔德:"正确答案是D,A和B,没有C.当然如果巴黎的研究走向另一个方面,我会考虑更改答案,但是我们需要等到94年春天."
Rosenfeld: Well the correct answer is D) A and B but not C.Of course if the study in Paris goes the other way, I will consider changing the answer, but we'll have to wait until spring of 94.
杰森:"恩,唔,好吧,看看第五题,正确答案是B,儿童多动症是心理和生理上的紊乱.这个判错了."
Jason: Uh hu.Ok, look at number five.The correct answer is checked B.Hyperkinesias is a physiological and psychological disorder.It's marked wrong.
罗森费尔德:"没错,确实是错的."
Rosenfeld: Sure.Because it is wrong.
杰森:"从什么时候?"
Jason: Since when?
罗森费尔德:"自从库坦伯尔斯博士新近的白鼠项目之后."
Rosenfeld: Since Dr Kurtenbowers recent project with white rats.
杰森:"什么?"
Jason: Pardon me?
罗森费尔德:"抱歉,我知道你的观点在某些圈子里可能会被认为是正确的."
Rosenfeld: I'm sorry, I can see where your point of view might be considered correct, in some circles.
杰森:"好的,那么我们两个都没错."
Jason: Ok, and so we are both right.
罗森费尔德:"对,但是是我在教这门课程,所以我相对地更准确一些."
Rosenfeld: Yeah.But I'm teaching the class, which makes me more right.
杰森:"啊?"
Jason: What?
罗森费尔德:"西佛尔博士,我要怎么说呢?我建议你要从一个父亲的角度看待你儿子的作业,而不是从专业人士的角度出发,我肯定至少在你自己的小世界里是这样的."
Rosenfeld: Dr Seaver, how can I say this?I suggest that you are looking at your son's work through a father's eyes and not through the eyes of a competent professional.Which of course I'm sure you are in your own little world.
杰森:"我不是从那个角度看待我儿子的作业的."
Jason: I'm not looking at my sons work that way.
罗森费尔德:"是的,你是."
Rosenfeld: Yes you are.
杰森:"我不是."
Jason: Am not.
罗森费尔德:"是的,你是."
Rosenfeld: Yes you are.
杰森:"我不是."
Jason: AM not.
罗森费尔德:"是,是,是."
Rosenfeld: Are are are.
杰森:"不是,不是,不是.你瞧,这不是我儿子的作业,朋友,老兄,好排挡,这是我自己做的."
Jason: Am not, not, not.Look, this is not my sons work bob, pal, best mate.I wrote these answers myself.
罗森费尔德:"那么我肯定应该重判了."
Rosenfeld: Well then I definitely should re-evaluate this grade.
杰森:"非常感谢,我希望如此,您用的是红色的笔."
Jason: Thank you very much.I should hope so.You are using a red pen.
罗森费尔德:"不,深红色."
Rosenfeld: No.Crimson.
茱丽:"等一下,我就来."
Julie: Just a minute.I'm coming.
麦克:"送给茱丽科斯泰勒的花."
Mike: Flowers for Julie Costello.
茱丽:"这是谁送的呢?"
Julie: Who are they from?
麦克:"你的秘密男友."
Mike: Your secret boyfriend.
茱丽:"莫里斯"
Julie: Maurice?
麦克:"不是,另外一个."
Mike: No, the other one.
茱丽:"有问题,不,你的书呢?我本想今晚一起学习心理学的."
Julie: Something's wrong.No, where are your books?I thought we were studying for psych tonight.
麦克:"你想不想站在斯坦顿渡口的甲板上在微风下看着落日余晖和曼哈顿的灯火阑珊?"
Mike: How would you like to stand on the wind blown deck of the Stanton island ferry and watch the sun go down and the lights of Manhattan come up?
茱丽:"恩,你跟我一起吗?"
Julie: Uh.Would you be with me?
麦克:"我当然跟你一起了."
Mike: Of course I'd be with you.
茱丽:"那我不想去了."
Julie: Then I don't want to go.
麦克:"你说什么?"
Mike: What?
茱丽:"麦克,你不能一直这么无视你心理学课程上的问题."
Julie: Mike, you can't keep ignoring your problems in psych class.
麦克:"我没有,我放弃那门课了."
Mike: I'm not.I'm dropping the class.
茱丽:"你什么?但是你……"
Julie: You're what?But you...
麦克:"听我说,听我说,在你说话之前,你还记得我要你一直提醒我学习的事情吗?"
Mike: Listen listen.Before you say another word, do you remember how I asked you to constantly remind me to study?
茱丽:"是的."
Julie: Yeah.
麦克:"那么我不想你再做那些了."
Mike: Well I no longer want you to do that anymore.
茱丽:"为什么?"
Julie: Why?
麦克:"因为你总是提醒我要学习."
Mike: Because you constantly remind me to study.
茱丽:"但是你说……"
Julie: But you said...
麦克:"嘿,茱丽,我已经下决心放弃这门课程了,好了,现在我们为什么不能横跨纽约市享受一个浪漫的夜晚呢?"
Mike: Hey Julie.I've made up my mind about this class thing.Ok.Now can't we have a nice romantic evening involving two birds over the city of New York?
茱丽:"好吧,我去拿外套."
Julie: Ok, I'll get my coat.
麦克:"好的,我甚至还预订了晚餐."
Mike: Ok.I even made dinner reservations.
茱丽:"那一定会很有趣,现在我们能待在一起真好."
Julie: Well this will be fun.And it's good that we're spending time together now.
麦克:"你说现在是什么意思?"
Mike: What do you mean now?
茱丽:"你还要把这门课程补上,而且要仔细想想你我们的暑假计划,那会是很棒的计划."
Julie: Well you'll have to make up this class, and that pretty much takes care of our summer plans, and...they were great plans.
麦克:"可能是我有一点过于心急了."
Mike: Well maybe I was being a little over hasty.
茱丽:"你真是这么认为的吗?"
Julie: Do you think so?
麦克:"是的,没错,我是说,嘿,这个学期我已经上了一半了,如果我能再多坚持几周."
Mike: Yeah, yeah.I mean hey, I'm half way through the semester already ad if I can just hang in there a couple more weeks,
茱丽:"如果这是你想做的……"
Julie: Well if that's what you want to do...
麦克:"哦,是的,哦,是的,我应该去学习.但是,恩,我的书还在家里,所以,听着,我们改天再出去,好吧."
Mike: Oh yeah, Oh yeah.I should study.But uh, I left my books at home, so listen, we are going to have to go out another night.Ok.
茱丽:"今晚我很希望出去的啊."
Julie: And I was looking so forward to going out tonight.
麦克:"是吗,改天见吧,嘿,至少我不用再复习操纵那一章了."
Mike: Yeah.See you.Hey, at least I won't have to review the chapter on manipulation.
麦克:"嘿,妈妈."
Mike: Hey mum.
麦琪:"嘿,麦克,我还以为你在外面吃晚饭呢."
Maggie: Hey Mike.I thought you were eating out.
麦克:"我也这么想的,晚饭吃什么?"
Mike: So did I.What's for dinner?
麦琪:"这个我也想知道,你看到你父亲了吗?"
Maggie: That's what id like to know.Have you seen your father?
麦克:"好几次."
Mike: Many times.
麦琪:"他晚饭什么也没做."
Maggie: He didn't make anything for dinner.
麦克:"嘿,妈妈,不要告诉爸爸,我觉得他心不在焉."
Mike: Hey mum, between the two of us, I think the man's slipped a clog.
麦琪:"不,不,不,亲爱的,他一直都是那样."
Maggie: No, no, no honey.He has always been that way.
杰森:"大家好,我给大家买了豆沙饼."
Jason: Hello.I brought a hummus for everyone.
麦琪:"你又在打什么主意."
Maggie: You might be on to something.
杰森:"好了,别拐弯抹角了?"
Jason: Ok, why beat around the bush.
麦克:"灌木丛?"
Mike: Bush?
杰森:"灌木,矮树,美国总统."
Jason: Shrub, small tree, president of the United States.
麦琪:"你肯定是在打什么鬼主意."
Maggie: You're definitely on to something.
杰森:"我必须先说明我的本意不是这样的."
Jason: I'll be the first to concede that things didn't go exactly as I'd planned.
麦琪:"出什么事情了?"
Maggie: What things?
杰森:"好吧,我告诉你们,但是别忘了好事多磨."
Jason: Ok, I'll tell you.But keep in mind there is some good news.All the way at the end.
麦琪:"为什么我们不能先听到好事?"
Maggie: Why don't we come right to the good news.
杰森:"好事就是我相信麦克."
Jason: The good news is I believe in Mike.
麦克:"谢谢你."
Mike: Thank you.
麦琪:"还有别的什么事?"
Maggie: And the other news?
杰森:"我今天去见了你的心理学教授."
Jason: I met your psychology professor today.
麦克和麦琪:"你说什么?"
Mike and Maggie: What?
麦琪:"你先告诉我不要去,然后自己又去了."
Maggie: You went down there after telling me not to.
麦克:"爸爸,这可能是你所做的最糟糕的事情了."
Mike: Dad, that is the worst thing you could possibly have done.
杰森:"这也正是我对你妈妈所说的."
Jason: That's exactly what I told your mother.
麦克:"真不敢相信,我爸爸竟然去见我的大学教授!我怎么还能有脸再去学校呢?"
Mike: I can't believe this.My daddy goes to see my college professor!How am I supposed to show my face there again?
杰森:"麦克,别这样,我不是作为你的父亲去的,我是作为你教授的同行.好了,我觉得你也区分不出这两者之间的区别,对吧?"
Jason: Mike, come on.I didn't go down there as your father.I went down as a colleague.Alright, I see you are having trouble making the distinction here, right?
麦克:"你没有给他带去豆沙饼吧,对吧?"
Mike: You didn't bring him hummus, did you?
杰森:"没有"
Jason: No.
麦克:"这还好,那么我明天还有脸面去见他."
Mike: Well good, because I got to go face that guy in the morning.
杰森:"我还以为你放弃这门课程了呢."
Jason: I thought you gave up that class.
麦克:"我已经改变主意了."
Mike: I changed my mind.
杰森:"你为什么要这么做呢,麦克?你是对的,他是个笨蛋,你永远都不会得到公正的分数."
Jason: What did you do that for Mike?You were right about that guy.He's a bozo.You're never going to get a fair shake.
麦琪:"杰森,你在说什么?"
Maggie: Jason, what are you doing?
杰森:"相信我."
Jason: Trust me.
麦琪:"我才不要."
Maggie: Not a chance.
麦克:"这学期我才上了一半,我还能把补交作业的那个D扳平."
Mike: I was half way through the semester.I just have to make up that D I got on the make up assignment.
杰森:"恩,我对他说你作业上的答案都是正确的,所以,恩,你得到的不再是个D了."
Jason: Yeah, well I told him that all the answers on that test were correct.And so, um, you don't exactly have a D on it anymore.
麦琪:"哦,哦!你这是什么意思?"
Maggie: Uh oh!What do you mean?
麦克:"你的意思是你让他改了我的成绩?好了,爸爸,噢,你真是能给我添麻烦."
Mike: You mean you got him to change my grade?Alright dad.Wow.You can embarrass me any day.
杰森:"好了,我说实话,当时,我提到了,我对他说,那作业是我做的,所以他就改了你的成绩,你最后得了个F."
Jason: Ok, I'll be frank.And I also, while I was there I mentioned that I'd, I said to him that, I, I myself wrote the answers, and so, uh, he changed your grade and you have an F.
麦琪:"什么?"
Maggie: What?
麦克:"什么?"
Mike: What?
杰森:"计划不是这样的,麦琪."
Jason: It wasn't part of the plan Maggie.
麦琪:"哦,杰森,你就不应该这样计划."
Maggie: Oh Jason, you shouldn't have even had a plan.
麦克:"哦,那么我现在努力学习去扳回这个F?"
Mike: Oh, so now I've got to go and work off an F?
杰森:"哦,那个,好象你以前从来没有得过F."
Jason: Oh what, like you've never had an F before.
麦琪:"杰森!"
Maggie: Jason!
杰森:"抱歉,我也很难过,我以前也从没有得过F.现在是我刚才说过的宣布好事的最合适的时机了."
Jason: I'm sorry.I'm upset.I've never had an F before.And may I remind you this is the proper place for that good news I mentioned earlier.
麦琪:"好事是什么?"
Maggie: What good news?
杰森:"就是我相信麦克,是的!"
Jason: That I believe in Mike.Yes!
麦克:"爸爸,到下次我再让你帮我检查作业就得再等12年了."
Mike: Dad, it will be another twelve years before I show you my homework.
杰森:"哦,如果是这种态度的话,你只能得到同样的成绩.你相信这家伙吗?我是说他会从所有这一切中吸取教训吗?生活不是只有唯一的答案,通常人们对待你的方式都不公正.有时父亲会因为关心孩子而做出一些傻事.但是,不是这样的.他得到的教训是什么?不要给他看我的家庭作业,孩子,亲爱的."
麦琪:"如我所见."
00:21:45,900
Jason: Oh, with that attitude you'll still be in the same grade.Can you believe this guy?I mean with all the things he could have leaned out of this.That there are no pad answers in life.That occasionally people are going to treat you unfairly.That sometimes a father gets a little nutty when he's looking out for his kid.But no.What does he take home?Don't show him my homework.Boy.Honey. Maggie: Works for me.